<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">ComputerScientists</string>
    <string name="charles_babbage" translatable="false">Charles Babbage</string>
    <string name="charles_babbage_picture_cd" translatable="false">Picture of Charles Babbage in 1860</string>
    <string name="charles_babbage_overview">Charles Babbage, FRS (26 December 1791 – 18 October 1871) was an English polymath. He was a mathematician, philosopher, inventor and mechanical engineer, who is best remembered now for originating the concept of a programmable computer.Considered a "father of the computer", Babbage is credited with inventing the first mechanical computer that eventually led to more complex designs. His varied work in other fields has led him to be described as "pre-eminent" among the many polymaths of his century.Parts of Babbage\'s uncompleted mechanisms are on display in the London Science Museum. In 1991, a perfectly functioning difference engine was constructed from Babbage\'s original plans. Built to tolerances achievable in the 19th century, the success of the finished engine indicated that Babbage\'s machine would have worked.</string>
    <string name="tim_berners_lee" translatable="false">Tim Berners-Lee</string>
    <string name="tim_berners_lee_picture_cd" translatable="false">Picture of Berners-Lee in 2008</string>
    <string name="tim_berners_lee_overview">Sir Timothy John "Tim" Berners-Lee, OM, KBE, FRS, FREng, FRSA, DFBCS (born 8 June 1955), also known as "TimBL," is a British computer scientist, best known as the inventor of the World Wide Web. He made a proposal for an information management system in March 1989, and he implemented the first successful communication between a Hypertext Transfer Protocol (HTTP) client and server via the Internet sometime around mid November.Berners-Lee is the director of the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C), which oversees the Web\'s continued development. He is also the founder of the World Wide Web Foundation, and is a senior researcher and holder of the Founders Chair at the MIT Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory (CSAIL). He is a director of the Web Science Research Initiative (WSRI), and a member of the advisory board of the MIT Center for Collective Intelligence.In 2004, Berners-Lee was knighted by Queen Elizabeth II for his pioneering work. In April 2009, he was elected a foreign associate of the United States National Academy of Sciences. He was honoured as the "Inventor of the World Wide Web" during the 2012 Summer Olympics opening ceremony, in which he appeared in person, working with a vintage NeXT Computer at the London Olympic Stadium. He tweeted "This is for everyone", which was instantly spelled out in LCD lights attached to the chairs of the 80,000 people in the audience.</string>

</resources>